{"tossups": [{"question": "The catalyst for this event was Frank Wills discovering tape keeping some doors from latching. The men evolved in that portion of this event were found to be closely affiliated with CRP [\u201ccreep\u201d]. The bulk of this event hinged on a refusal to release evidence despite a subpoena being issued for those (*) tapes. This event saw the President attempt to exercise executive privilege in order to avoid releasing those unedited tapes to a committee. For 10 points, name this scandal, named for the complex housing the DNC headquarters, the main cause of the resignation of Richard Nixon.", "answer": "Watergate Scandal [prompt on \u201cNixon scandal\u201d or similar until \u201cshared its name\u201d and accept Nixon v U.S. until \u201cthis scandal\u201d]", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "In this novel, a thief with a sweet tooth is convinced to steal a bedsheet in exchange for some dates. A doctor who shares a tent with Chief White Halfoat is declared dead after his name is found on McWatt\u2019s flight register. An Anabaptist in this work is interrogated as to whether he signed (*) \u201cWashington Irving\u201d to documents. At the end of this novel, the protagonist is given the idea to escape to Sweden by his tent-mate Orr. For 10 points, name this work set in Pianosa in which Yossarian attempts to get out of flying more missions, written by Joseph Heller.", "answer": "Catch-22", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The dome of the Dome of the Rock is currently made out of a kind of this medium. A group of over one thousand plaques in this medium were created by the Edo people in the Benin Kingdom, while a series of the \u201cRitual\u201d kind of this medium were found in ancient Chinese tombs. Works made in this medium are often created in the (*) lost-wax casting process. Many Greek sculptures such as Doryphoros and Discobolus were created in this medium but the Roman copies of these were made of marble because it was cheaper. For 10 points, name this metal that is an alloy consisting mostly of copper.", "answer": "Bronze", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Other", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Objects with this quality, which also must have being, make up the population of Meinong's Jungle. Alexius Meinong also created an ontology in which beings with this quality are included in the least restrictive subset called absistence. In one of Bertrand Russell\u2019s paradoxes, this quality is attributed to the \u201cpresent king of France,\u201d (*) since France is presently a republic. Objects with this quality exist in separate \u201cuniverses of discourse\u201d and do not have physical referents. For 10 points, identify this quality of all things that exist only in one\u2019s imagination.", "answer": "Imaginary [accept any answer mentioning \u201cNot real\u201d]", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "One disease treated by this compound causes patients to exhibit a characteristic \u201cstrawberry tongue.\u201d While that illness, Kawasaki disease, mainly affects children, this drug shouldn\u2019t normally be administered to children for fear of developing (*) Reye's syndrome. Other diseases treated by this drug include pericarditis and rheumatoid arthritis. This nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory drug is also known as acetylsalicylic acid and has been historically harvested from willow trees. For 10 points, name this drug developed by Bayer that treats pain, fever, and inflammation.", "answer": "Aspirin [accept Acetylsalicylic acid before mentioned]", "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This deity married Buddhi and Siddhi, the personifications of wisdom and prudence. This deity almost ate Kubera\u2019s palace until his father gave him a handful of rice, and this deity beats his peacock-riding brother (*) Skanda in a contest to see who could travel around the world the fastest. This deity was formed when his mother breathed life into a clay figure. That woman is Parvati. Known as the \u201cremover of obstacles\u201d by devotees is, for 10 points, what elephant-headed god from Hindu mythology?", "answer": "Ganesha [accept Ganesh or Ganapati]", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "This man and John Glenn were the only members of the Keating Five to avoid any punishment. His decision to forgo a cross party presidential ticket with a Connecticut Democrat was chronicled in the book Game Change. A more well-known example of his bipartisan bridge-building was the 2002 act named for him and Wisconsin\u2019s (*) Russ Feingold, which was overturned by Citizens United in 2010. After this man\u2019s 2017 cancer diagnosis, Lindsey Graham noted that nothing could compare to his torture as a prisoner in Vietnam. For 10 points, name this maverick Arizona Senator who was defeated by Barack Obama in the 2008 election.", "answer": "John S. McCain III", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "A leader of this country developed the \u201cPerson Dignity Theory\u201d as its governing ideology to oppose the spread of communism. That man\u2019s brother would defeat the former emperor of this country in a 1955 referendum but would lose power following his disastrous handling of the Buddhist Crisis. (*) Afterwards, Duong Van Minh staged a coup in this country and executed both Ngo Dinh Nhu and Ngo Dinh Diem. For 10 points, name this Southeast Asian country reunified with its northern neighbor following the withdrawal of U.S. forces.", "answer": "South Vietnam [prompt on \u201cVietnam\u201d; do NOT prompt on or accept \u201cNorth Vietnam\u201d]", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "One of this man\u2019s works features a protagonist who wanders aimlessly through an unspecified German city. That character is an autobiographical representation of the author and his feelings of alienations with society at large. (*) In addition to writing about Harry Haller, this author wrote of a protagonist who becomes rich under the businessman Kamaswami and learns to lust after the courtesan Kamala. That protagonist attempts to find his own path to enlightenment after meeting the Buddha with his friend Govinda. For 10 points, name this German author who wrote Steppenwolf and Siddhartha.", "answer": "Herman Hesse", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Yang and Mills created a theory of this force that is a non-abelian gauge theory. Another theory describing this force has a lattice variety, and that theory describing this force takes place in an SU(3) symmetry group. Pions were believed to carry this force but it is now known that this is mediated by the exchange of (*) gluons. Color confinement is a consequence of this force that is described by quantum chromodynamics, or QCD. For 10 points, name this force that confines quarks into hadrons, is the most powerful of the four fundamental forces, and holds atomic nuclei together.", "answer": "Strong Nuclear Force", "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "Hugo Winckler discovered tablets in Boghazkoy that described peace negotiations after this battle. The Poem and the Bulletin describe this battle in great detail, and after this battle was finished, its winner sacked Dapur and Tunip. Two Shasu spies were captured during this battle, which saw mercenaries from the Amurru and (*) Ptah divisions force one side to retreat across the Orontes River. After this battle, Muwatalli II and its victor signed the first-ever recorded peace treaty. For 10 points, name this largest chariot battle which saw Ramesses the Great defeat the Hittites.", "answer": "Battle of Kadesh", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "The Synod of Dort was called to defend this faith against the rise of Arminianism, although it would also lay the seeds for the Methodist split. The founder of this faith cooperated with the Catholic inquisition to persecute Michael Servetus, who criticized his magnum opus. (*) The abbreviated mnemonic TULIP is often used to outline this faith\u2019s doctrines, which include unconditional election and the perseverance of the saints. For 10 points, name this protestant denomination of Christianity that has its ideals outlined in the Institutes of the Christian Religion and is named after a French theologian.", "answer": "Calvinism", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "When two of these objects meet, it is possible that a Wadati-Benioff zone will form, as well as an accretionary wedge. Their elevations are controlled by isostasy and their relative buoyancy. Explanations for these objects\u2019 behavior are the tidal forces of the Sun and Moon and their greater mechanical strength than the (*) asthenosphere. Two of these bodies separate at a rift valley, a famous one of which is in the Mid-Atlantic Ridge. For 10 points, name these sections of the Earth\u2019s lithosphere that move around and contribute to the theory of continental drift.", "answer": "Tectonic plate [prompt on partial answer]", "subcategory": "Science Other", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "An opera by this man takes place in Texarkana and is about the title woman being thrown into a wasp\u2019s nest and being rescued by Remus. This composer, who wrote A Guest of Honor about Booker T. Washington, wrote that opera, (*) Treemonisha. Syncopations were a noted part of one of his works, and his most famous piece is associated with Sedalia, Missouri and was called \u201cMaple Leaf Rag.\u201d For 10 points, name this American composer who was known as the \u201cKing of Ragtime.\u201d", "answer": "Scott Joplin", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "A giant one of these entities is a member of the Devil\u2019s Entourage and has a love of pickled mushrooms; that character is Behemoth. Another of these is called Church after Winston Churchill and is killed after being (*) hit by a truck in a Stephen King novel. One of these creatures is kept by Holly Golightly in Truman Capote\u2019s Breakfast at Tiffany\u2019s. For 10 points, name the title \u201cpractical\u201d animals of a T.S. Eliot collection written under the alias of \u201cOld Possum,\u201d the namesakes of an Andrew Lloyd Webber musical.", "answer": "Cats", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "This battle was preceded by the Battle of Ulm, and von Buxhowden\u2019s forces drowned in Lake Satschan while marching to this battle. During this battle, troops led by Marshal Soult captured the Pratzen Heights, which caused Mikhail Kutuzov to retreat. The Treaty of (*) Pressburg was signed after this battle, which led to the dissolution of the Holy Roman Empire. For 10 points, name this 1805 battle where Napoleon Bonaparte\u2019s army defeated a coalition of Austrian, German, and Russian forces.", "answer": "Battle of Austerlitz [accept Battle of the Three Emperors]", "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"question": "A well-known saying about this mountain is that a wise person will climb it once but a fool would climb it twice. The last known eruption of this volcano started in 1707 and created a second peak on its southeastern side. It is located on the triple junction of the Amurian Plate, Okhotsk Plate, and (*) Philippine Sea Plate. A forest located at its base has been the site of many disappearances and is known as Aokigahara. It is known as one of the \u201cThree Holy Mountains,\u201d along with Mount Tate and Mount Haku. For 10 points, name this tallest mountain in Japan, known for its symmetry.", "answer": "Mount Fuji [do NOT prompt on or accept Fiji]", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "To avoid obscuring this non-American building, other buildings in the city typically do not surpass twelve floors in height. This building has a curved-in ceiling and floor to negate the optical illusion of them bowing outwards. The alternating triglyphs and metopes above the architrave are elements of the (*) Ionic order, while the bare columns suggest a Doric order. The pediment of this building contained sculptures now in the British Museum, called the Elgin Marbles, while the internal cella housed a large statue of Athena, which was the namesake of this building. For 10 points, name this ancient temple on the Acropolis in Athens.", "answer": "Parthenon", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Other", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This law can be applied to ionic solutions through the Sechenov equation. This law is applied in geochemistry in order to determine the potential volatility of magma. This law acts as an analogue to Raoult\u2019s Law in low concentration solutions. This law explains the formation of bubbles of oxygen and nitrogen in the joints and bloodstream of (*) deep sea divers, leading to a condition known as \u201cthe bends.\u201d For 10 points, name this law, shown in action whenever a soda is opened, which states that the amount of gas that can dissolve in a liquid is proportional to the partial pressure.", "answer": "Henry\u2019s Law", "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This author\u2019s poem \u201cThe Gods of the Copybook Headings\u201d was included in T.S. Eliot\u2019s namesake collection of this author\u2019s poems. This author\u2019s poem about Victorian-era manliness was addressed to his son, John, and begins with (*) \u201cIf you can keep your head when all about you.\u201d This author\u2019s poem about an English soldier in India who regrets the death of the title character, a bhisti, ends with the famous line, \u201cYou\u2019re a better man than I am, Gunga Din!\u201d For 10 points, name this British author of \u201cThe White Man\u2019s Burden\u201d and \u201cMandalay,\u201d also known for his novel, The Jungle Book.", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling Tiebreaker", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "A shield with a lion and dolphin sits in front of St. George\u2019s Cross on a flag commemorating this event. Gustave Mesny and Jean-Baptiste Molinie defended the city of Lille during this event to ensure its success, and an event similar to this one, known as Operation Cycle, was done at (*) Le Havre. This event, which was codenamed Operation Dynamo, was only able to succeed because German tanks got stuck in mud. Eight hundred fifty \u201clittle ships\u201d sailed from Ramsgate during this event. For 10 points, name this event which saw thousands of British and French troops being evacuated from the namesake French city.", "answer": "Evacuation from Dunkirk [accept Operation Dynamo before mentioned] Packet 8 \u2013 Bonuses", "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "A coat of gold, a coat of red, a lion still has claws. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Plantagenets", "Edward the Black Prince [or Edward of Woodstock; prompt on \u201cEdward\u201d; prompt on \u201cthe Black Prince\u201d]", "Peasants"], "parts": ["Name this English royal house that suffered brutal infighting during the Wars of the Roses. Their coat of arms featured three golden lions on a red backdrop.", "The dynasty might not have reached such an unceremonious end had this exceptional son of Edward III not died a year before his father. His son Richard II helped destabilize the country for good.", "The first challenge to Richard II\u2019s rule was a rebellion of these people led by Wat Tyler. They are distinguished from serfs because they own their own land, an unexpected benefit of the Black Death."], "subcategory": "History British", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer these questions about songs in <em>Fantasia 2000</em>.", "answers_sanitized": ["Pines of Rome", "The Firebird", "The Sorcerer\u2019s Apprentice"], "parts": ["In the animation for this piece, a family of humpback whales are able to fly. This piece was part of a trio of tone poems by Ottorino Respighi that also includes depictions of festivals and fountains in the title Italian city.", "This piece by Igor Stravinsky is made to depict the story of an elk that awakens the title creature in the film. This ballet originally featured Prince Ivan and the magical title avian.", "This piece by Paul Dukas is the only piece to feature in both Fantasia 2000 and the original Fantasia. The bassoon is the first instrument to play the first full statement of the main melody in this piece that has a title referring to Mickey in the film."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "The constant associated with this quantity is symbolized K. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Reaction rate", "Arrhenius Equation", "Transition States"], "parts": ["Name this quantity that quantifies how fast a reaction proceeds.", "This equation, named for a Swedish scientist, states that the rate constant is proportional to e to the activation energy over RT.", "Hammond\u2019s Postulate states that the energy of these entities is related to what a compound will look like at these entities. These states are defined as the highest potential energy on a reaction diagram, and the double dagger symbol is used to indicate that the variable is measured at these states."], "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This author, whose real name was Eric Blair, supposedly chose his pen name because of his love for a river in Suffolk. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["George Orwell", "Animal Farm", "Burma [accept Myanmar]"], "parts": ["Name this English author who wrote about Winston Smith living under the tyranny of Big Brother in 1984.", "George Orwell also wrote this novel that serves as an allegory for communism and features the horse Boxer and pig Snowball.", "Before becoming an author, Orwell worked as a police officer in this then-British colony. His time in this colony inspired his essays \u201cA Hanging\u201d and \u201cShooting an Elephant.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "In 2016, this man threw his mouth guard at a Cleveland Cavaliers fan in frustration. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Stephen Curry", "Akron", "Georgetown University"], "parts": ["Name this Golden State Warriors point guard. Forming the \u201cSplash Brothers\u201d with Klay Thompson, in the 2015-16 season, he became the first NBA player to make four hundred three pointers in one season.", "In a strange coincidence, both Curry and LeBron James were delivered at the same hospital in this Ohio city. A traditional center of the rubber industry, this city is home to Goodyear Tires.", "Curry gained fame in college for leading his Davidson Wildcats past this Big East powerhouse in the 2008 NCAA tournament. Though this Washington, D.C. school\u2019s mascot is a bulldog, their team nickname is Latin for \u201cwhat is it.\u201d"], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "In this play, a character is arrested for criticizing Oronte\u2019s poem. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["The Misanthrope, or the Cantankerous Lover [accept Le Misanthrope ou l'Atrabilaire amoureux]", "Moliere [accept Jean-Baptiste Poquelin]", "French"], "parts": ["Name this play in which Alceste pines for the love of Celimene. At the end of this play, Eliante and Philinte attempt to stop Alceste from running away.", "This author and philosopher wrote The Misanthrope. He also wrote about the title character\u2019s manipulations of Orgon in Tartuffe.", "Moliere wrote his works primarily in this language. Other writers in this language include Stendhal and George Sand."], "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "A group opposed to this agreement was led by Subcommander Marcos, who declared war on the federal government in the state of Chiapas. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["North American Free Trade Agreement", "State of Israel", "Oriental Republic of Uruguay"], "parts": ["Name this trilateral trade deal between Canada, the U.S., and Mexico, which went into effect in 1994. Donald Trump referred to this agreement as \u201cthe worst trade deal\u201d in history at a 2016 debate.", "While NAFTA was the first multilateral free trade agreement the U.S. joined, a bilateral agreement with this country was ratified ten years earlier. Negotiations were conducted while this country\u2019s prime minister was Shimon Peres [shee-MOHN PEH-rehs].", "The World Trade Organization was created after a \u201cround\u201d of negotiations took place named for this South American country. Those negotiations took place in the resort town of Punta del Este and featured a speech by this country\u2019s first democratic president, Julio Sanguinetti [sahn-ghee-NEH-tee]."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer some questions about techniques in music playing.", "answers_sanitized": ["Pizzicato", "Harmonic", "Vibrato"], "parts": ["This technique refers to when a string player plucks the strings of his or her instrument. Johann Strauss II wrote a polka based off of this technique.", "To play the \u201cartificial\u201d type of this effect, a string player holds down one note and lightly touches a higher note on the same string. Both the \u201cartificial\u201d and \u201cnatural\u201d types of this effect work by canceling out the fundamental tone.", "This technique refers to a pulsating change in pitch. On string instruments, this effect is achieved by waggling the finger on the fingerboard; on wind instruments, it is done by modulating air flow."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "Koppen names one classification system for these entities. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Climate", "Pressure", "Milankovitch Cycle"], "parts": ["Name this long term pattern of weather that often has its \u201cchange\u201d attributed to global warming.", "Climate scientists measure this meteorological variable, whose gradient causes wind. It can be measured in Pascals, millibars, or millimeters of mercury.", "These cycles measure the effect that eccentricity, tilt, and precession have upon climate. They are named for the Serbian geophysicist who discovered them."], "subcategory": "Science Other", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This religion recognizes a number of messiahs, among them Cyrus the Great. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Judaism [accept word forms]", "Philistines", "Ark of the Covenant [accept Ark of the Testimony or Tabot]"], "parts": ["Name this first truly monotheist religion, sects of which include Reform and Orthodox. It was begun by a Babylonian convert named Abram.", "The early Jews had a number of enemies, among them, this group that waged war against them a number of times. They were beaten back by Hezekiah and when David slew Goliath but they were victorious over King Saul.", "This relic was captured by the Philistines at the Battle of Aphek but was returned after God smote the Philistines with famine and hemorrhoids. Allegedly, this relic was taken to Ethiopia after being lost at a later time."], "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "Genevieve Nnaji and Mercy Johnson are actresses in this country\u2019s film industry. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Federal Republic of Nigeria", "Oil [accept Petroleum]", "Igbo"], "parts": ["Name this country, which is predicted to have the sixth-largest population by 2030. This country\u2019s Nollywood film industry is centered in its largest city of Lagos.", "This important Nigerian resource was discovered at Nembe Creek and Owerri in the Niger River Delta. Today, Royal Dutch Shell processes this resource in the city of Port Harcourt.", "This ethnic majority, whose members include Chinua Achebe, live in the southern part of Nigeria. They temporarily seceded from Nigeria during the Biafra War."], "category": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "Poetry in the twentieth century was largely focused on empowerment. Name some female poets from this time period. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Alice Walker", "Audre Lorde", "Maya Angelou"], "parts": ["This author of The Third Life of Grange Copeland also wrote the critically-acclaimed novel The Color Purple.", "This author describes her own struggles with her homosexuality in her novel The Black Unicorn and her ultimately fatal battle with cancer in her Cancer Journals.", "Perhaps the most well-known female poet of her time, this woman is the author of The Heart of a Woman and I Know Why the Caged Bird Sings."], "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, identify these terms dealing with anatomical positions of the body.", "answers_sanitized": ["Anterior [accept Ventral]", "Bilateral", "Transverse"], "parts": ["This term is used for structures closer to the front of the body and is opposite of the dorsal or posterior side.", "This type of symmetry refers to when two identical structures are paired on the body, with one on each side, such as the ears or arms.", "This plane divides the body into top and bottom portions, whereas the coronal plane divides front and back and the sagittal plane divides the body into left and right."], "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Abraham Lincoln issued the Emancipation Proclamation immediately after this battle. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Battle of Antietam [accept Battle of Sharpsburg]", "George Brinton McClellan", "Cigars"], "parts": ["Name this battle which Robert E. Lee lost during his Maryland Campaign. The majority of the fighting during this battle occurred in the Dunker Church cornfield and near \u201cBloody Lane.\u201d", "The Union forces at Antietam were commanded by this general. Because of his failure in pursuing Lee, he was fired by Lincoln, whom he ran against in the Election of 1864.", "Before the battle, McClellan\u2019s troops found Lee\u2019s battle plans wrapped around three of these things. The CIA attempted to kill Fidel Castro with one of these that exploded."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Peter Singer is known as one of the most influential philosophers of our time. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Ethics", "Animals", "Utilitarianism"], "parts": ["Name the branch of philosophy that analyzes what is right and wrong. Peter Singer made his name in its \u201capplied\u201d field.", "Peter Singer published a monumental ethical tract arguing that this category of non-human entities deserves moral consideration as a result of their consciousness. PETA thinks it\u2019s unethical to eat them.", "Singer notably developed a \u201cpreference theory\u201d to this school of moral philosophy first articulated by John Stuart Mill and Jeremy Bentham."], "category": "Philosophy"}, {"leadin": "This dynasty\u2019s Zhengtong Emperor was kidnapped during the Tumu Crisis. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Ming Dynasty", "Yongle Emperor [accept Zhu Di]", "Forbidden City"], "parts": ["Name this dynasty which sponsored the voyages of Zheng He. Matteo Ricci was a Jesuit missionary who worked during this dynasty\u2019s reign, and they were known for their intricate porcelain designs.", "The aforementioned voyages of Zheng He were sponsored by this emperor. This emperor\u2019s minister Xie Jin compiled a list of all of the known Chinese texts.", "The Yongle Emperor ordered the construction of this palace complex in Beijing. It is composed of three main halls: the Halls of Supreme Harmony, Central Harmony, and Preserving Harmony."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Analyses of the human psyche, supernatural forces, tragic endings, and fatalistic humor - all of these can be found in the works of this short story author who died tragically at age thirty-five. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Ryunosuke Akutagawa [accept in either order]", "Japan", "Kazuo Ishiguro [accept in either order]"], "parts": ["This author wrote about three varying accounts of the murder of a samurai in \u201cIn a Grove\u201d and about the low-ranking official Goi in \u201cYam Gruel,\u201d in addition to writing \u201cRashomon.\u201d", "The Akutagawa Prize is a literary award given to new writers from this island country, which is also the home nation of Kenzaburo Oe.", "This Japanese-born British novelist author of The Remains of the Day and Never Let Me Go recently published a book about collective amnesia caused by a mist in The Buried Giant."], "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "The story of the Hall of Utgard-Loki is one of the strangest adventures of the Aesir. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Thor", "Cat", "Jotunheim"], "parts": ["Name this god who attempts to murder Utgard-Loki with his hammer several times throughout the adventure. Thankfully, this angry god of thunder fails to hurt anyone.", "Thor alarms Utgard-Loki by successfully lifting Jormungandr above his head while it is amusingly disguised as this furry animal.", "The gods meet Utgard-Loki in this land of frost giants and rock giants that is separated from Asgard by the river Iving."], "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, identify the artists of different works named <em>The Kiss</em>.", "answers_sanitized": ["Gustav Klimt", "Constantin Br\u00e2ncu\u0219i", "Auguste Rodin"], "parts": ["This Austrian artist painted The Kiss in the Art Nouveau style, depicting the embracing figures on a field of flowers. The background of his painting is entirely covered in gold leaf.", "This artist sculpted a severely abstracted version of The Kiss using unpolished limestone. His other sculptures include Endless Column, Princess X, and Bird in Space.", "This French artist took the figures of his The Kiss from a previous work of his, The Gates of Hell. While most of his works are in bronze, such as The Burghers of Calais, The Kiss is made out of marble."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "There are both stokes and anti-stokes varieties of the Raman type of this phenomenon. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Scattering", "Rayleigh scattering", "Four"], "parts": ["Identify this phenomenon that also has a Compton variety. The Raman type sees bound photons excited by colliding with another particle.", "This other type of scattering is why the sky turns blue and is contrasted with Mie scattering.", "The amount of scattering is inversely proportional to this power of the wavelength. Maxwell's equations consists of this many laws, and doubling the velocity increases the centripetal force by this factor."], "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}]}